# **ALINE SCHNEIDER**

Boca Raton, FL 33486 Portfolio: <u>alineschneider.com</u>

Phone: +1 561-283-9445 | Email: aline.schv@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/aline-schneider | Github: github.com/alineschneider

#### NICE TO MEET YOU!

I'm Aline, a Data Scientist with a motivation for drawing insights from data to inform decision-making, skilled in Python, Pandas, SQL, and data visualization tools. With an Engineering background, leadership experience and a certificate on Data Analytics and Visualization from UC Berkeley, I enjoy both working independently and in collaboration to solve challenging problems and drive growth.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages and Libraries: Python (Pandas, Numpy, scikit-learn), R (tidyverse: dplyr, tidyr,

ggplot2), JavaScript (D3, jQuery)

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy

Visualization: Tableau, Plotly, Geomapping (GeoJSON and Mapbox)

Web: HTML, CSS, Flask, APIs, Web Scraping, BeautifulSoup, Google Analytics

Machine Learning: Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random Forest, Support Vector

Machine, Neural Networks, Deep Learning

Software: Microsoft Office Specialist 2016 Excel Expert certification

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist2021 – presentPlaaceOslo, Norway

I analyze a broad range of data sets to extract business value and apply machine learning techniques to improve offering to clients on the platform.

#### Key Accomplishments:

• Creation of score system through PCA to map areas of the city with higher foot traffic to inform potential clients.

# Senior Optimization Analyst

2019 - 2020

**HiConversion** Florida, USA

I led the Optimization Analyst team, performed site audits and used customer data insights to develop A/B and multivariate testing strategies for e-commerce websites to improve user experience and increase revenue; analyzed the data and reported to stakeholders.

### Key Accomplishments:

- Promotion to Analyst Team Lead;
- Improved productivity through the creation of automated tools for repeated tasks.

#### **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Budget and Finance Analyst

2014 - 2017

**Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics (IBGE)** 

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

IBGE is a Brazilian Federal Government institution; the role involved analyzing data reports relative to financial expenses, warranties and security deposits by vendors.

# Administrative Analyst Vale S.A.

2011 – 2012

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Vale is a Brazilian metals and mining corporation, where I worked alongside a multidisciplinary team on a project, which included benchmarking visits and travelling to Vale's operation sites, identifying opportunities to improve productivity and providing tools for better visual management.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Data Analytics and Visualization Bootcamp Certificate: University of California, Berkeley** A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

B.S. in Civil Engineering: Universidade Federal do Espirito Santo, Vitoria, ES, Brazil

## **PROJECTS**

## The Platinum Lyric Project

2020

GitHub Repo: github.com/alineschneider/platinum lyric app Deployed App: platinum-lyric.herokuapp.com/

- The project aims to answer the question of whether a song's lyrics can predict its success, and exploring other possible factors that can contribute to that success.
- Core responsibilities: building the Python/Flask web application, its integration with the PostgreSQL database, hosted in AWS, and with the Machine Learning Model; Natural Language Processing of user input to feed into the model; Plotly visualizations to provide further insights into the data; app deployment to Heroku.

#### **LANGUAGES**

• Portuguese: native

English: bilingual proficiencyNorwegian: intermediate

French: basic